of the specialty utility at the point.
I am too's indication by Father of Sacred Heart Catholic Church,
Carl Kortner, Father of the United Kingdom.
Thank you very much.
At this time of the year, when Christians give special emphasis
to repentance and believe in the gospel,
as we prepare for the glorious celebration of Easter,
I share a prayer that scripture scholars consider
an insertion in the book of Daniel.
This community prayer was the first reading
for Mass Jester Day and is an acknowledgement
of public guilt and a supplication for the restoration
of sin.
And the name of Father of the Son, the Holy Spirit,
came in, a reading from the book of Daniel.
Lord, great and awesome God, you can keep your merciful
covenant or those who love you and absurd your commandments.
We have sin, been wicked and done evil.
We have rebelled and departed from your commandments
of the Holy Spirit.
We have not obeyed your servants, the prophets.
Who spoke in your name to our kings, our princes, our fathers,
and all the people of the land, justice,
O Lord, is on your side.
We are shamed faced even to this day.
We the men of Judah, the residents of Jerusalem,
and all Israel, near and far, and all the countries
to which you have scattered them,
because of their treachery toward you.
O Lord, we are shamed faced, flag our kings, our princes,
and our fathers, for having sin against you.
But your is a Lord, our God, our compassion and forgiveness.
Yeah, we rebel against you and pay no heed
to your command, O Lord, our God.
To live by the law, you gave us, for your servants,
the prophets, the name of Father of the Son,
and upon the Spirit, and upon the Holy Spirit.
And happy, say Joseph's name.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd like to read you through the flag
of the United States and Arabian, and to move it
about a level for which we stand.
One nation, I know God, individual,
liberty, justice, and all.
I am four as public input and unscheduled,
personal heritage, and we want any audience
wish to address these, and you tell the authority
on any agenda items.
There are being non item five as a consent agenda,
staff is recommending item six through eight,
which is claims minutes and a budget amendments
for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items,
then we'll obtain the motion to approve as recommended.
Motion to approve.
And the second please.
Well, call.
What's the, or get four-star?
Sure.
items nine, 10, 11, 12, and 13 are all the same.
and related to the same project. So we're going to ask Tyler and Sean to talk about all of them at once.
And we're going to go through and vote on them individually.
Hello, gentlemen.
All right.
Let's see.
So this is for the utility relocation for the ODOT 125 project.
Wester.
Relining the road, but the curve in, not in 90 out.
And we've got to write a lecture down there.
So these are the new utility easements to move out of their way.
And basically get back to maybe the similar way to that.
And Sean, I think you said in an earlier meeting or perhaps Tyler that the requirement, besides for safety reasons,
to change the angle of that curve is driven by the bridge.
Is that right?
The bridge project.
That's what we did.
Okay.
So building a new bridge, you can't have a sharp curve like that within a certain distance.
I'm assuming.
Okay.
The geometry of that basically from start to stop.
Three does that entire curve.
Okay.
And the city limits goes how far out there.
It doesn't go out that far, but our utility is going to go out that far.
Okay.
So we're just doing the utility relocation.
But the bonds that we spend will be reimbursed by ODOT.
Okay.
I understand where they're.
Because we're outside of right away from the entire route.
And they're moving.
And you're trying to use that.
Okay.
So we spend it first and get it back together.
And we are versusing our own private easement.
So another tip to use is that they want to widen that route or whatever.
Then we will be moving.
So.
Okay.
Right now you have the first offer letter that.
So I named it.
We'll present them.
The back concerns.
There with you.
So the values are based off of basically the ODOT project.
I did the braids.
Those.
And that by the braids.
All right.
So that's the compensation.
And so what's the landowners option when they receive the letter?
What do they do?
They'll get their letter.
They'll stay with them for 13 days.
Or you'll back and see if they set the offer.
They're not.
Hopefully they do because this is the same as what they're being offered.
They're impacted by the ODOT project.
Not all of them.
You have a right.
They take you.
So hopefully they accept these if they set the ODOT.
If not, then you go.
You go.
You go back.
Okay.
Who does that negotiate?
Right now.
So city is hired.
Universal field services.
As their land agent.
ODOT has this policy where they can't work for the design.
In general, they do the relocation.
So you hire all of them.
And Universal field services.
In Universal, they do.
There is a land agent for Oda on this project, so they're already talking to them in order to relationship.
And we'll be reimbursed for their services also.
And so the property owner has the right to say that's not enough, or except, and if it's not enough, then the negotiation process begins.
So when that offers come back to talk to us, ultimately Oda's paying for it.
So when they're not into the negotiation of it, I mean, we can sit there and say, yeah, but they don't have to reimbursed.
Well, if anybody wants anything outside of what the land agent suggested, we'll even know Oda and say, this is what they're wanting to do.
Before we bring it back, we'll change to that.
So we're not going to be left home with the bag for any amounts.
No, we'll see what they've done on their project.
Any other questions?
Anything else that we should know about this at this stage of the process?
No, I think the plan is done.
We have our OTA permit for it.
This is the last step if all we can get through is out there and move this on.
So what we're being asked to do is accept the utility easement offer in this day to James Sherry Cowan was the first one.
So in each case, we're being asked to accept the easement offer.
Thank you.
I have one more question.
With you guys had, if everything goes through and you guys are able to get out there and start making this happen, this movement.
How long of a time frame is this 7 months to take?
I don't think that's like it's to be estimated if we can figure it out.
And you're reimbursed.
And if we move here and we're all reimbursed.
It looks like, because the money's having plenty of federal government for some of this project.
So with this, we'll be about two months out there.
This is not going to cause any issues with your skirt staffing to fill your needs.
We would rather be doing other things, but I mean we'll make it work.
Okay, so I am nine.
The first one is accept the reject or excuse me.
I would recommend you accept utilities when offered a James Shoree callon.
We have a motion to approve.
I don't like it.
Second.
Roll call please.
Forced.
Aye.
And then the second part of that end, and the approved subsequent payment upon acceptance.
I'm going to accept the accept utility easement offer to Jean Ann Lambert, Ernest Patterson.
Thank you.
and his trusty at a genium would trust and approve subsequent payment upon acceptance of
offer.
Do we have a motion to approve 10?
Most of her.
Second.
The roll call please?
Or a certain.
Western.
Aye.
Or a good choice.
Item 11 is to accept utilities and offer the Gerald M. Lewis and Gwendolyn S. Lewis
and approve subsequent payment upon acceptance by the of all for by order.
We have a motion.
I'll second that.
Orcant.
Aye.
Western.
Forster.
Aye.
Item.
Which one do we just do 11?
Yep.
12 is accept utilities and offer to Jacqueline Don Lips and Julie John Lips.
And approve the subsequent payment upon acceptance of offer by order.
I'll make a motion to approve that.
Second.
Proof.
Authorities.
Solves.
Western.
Aye.
Orster.
Orcant.
13 is to accept utilities and offer.
Lance.
And approve the subsequent payment upon acceptance of offer by order.
We have a motion.
I'll second that.
Orcant.
All right.
So.
Western.
Aye.
Forster.
Thank you.
You need to cut that part of the tape.
OK.
Item 14 is new business.
Any new business for the special utility authority.
Item 15 is to have reports.
So in your packet stack is available for question.
Any questions for staff.
There being none.
Item 15 is trustee community announcements.
And the announcement to anyone.
Item 17 is a German.
Most of them.
I'll second that.
Orcant please.
Aye.
Solve.